把这个地方想像成美国地图
Think of this place like a map of the US.
我们的牢房那边  那是纽约城
Our cell over there, that's New York City.
医务室 我们的出口  是加利福尼亚
The infirmary, our exit, that's California.
我们脚下连接两边的管道...
The pipes beneath us that connect the two...
-66号公路  -我们要离开的必经之路
-Route 66.  -Our ticket out of here.
66公路直接在那个房子下面经过
Route 66 runs beneath that building.
那是管道上方的唯一建筑
It's the only building sitting on top of those tunnels.
我们要做的就是以P.I.的身份进里面去
All we gotta do is get in there,on PI,
给我们自己挖个出口
and dig ourselves an onramp.
-在哪?  -就这
-Which one?  -Right there.
这里4英尺下面连接主管道
This goes down four feet.Connects to the main line below.
我们要做的就是加宽它
All we've gotta do is widen it
这样66号公路就有了出口
and we've got ourselves an onramp to Route 66.
我要弄清楚
I'm gonna find out, you know,
你在上面干什么
what it is you're doing up there.
你说你到天花板上去
You told me that you had been up
是为了P.I.的工作 但...
in the crawlspace for PI,
P.I.从来没有派过这样的任务
and PI was never assigned to go there.
我们给你...
We got you...
一个小礼物
a little get well gift.
你叫什么?
What's your name?
发生了一起爆炸事故
There was an explosion.
煤气管道爆炸  里面所有人都死了
Gas line. Everyone inside was killed.
我们对抗的这伙人  不把我们干掉不会罢休的
These people won't stop until we're dead.
我们不能永远躲下去
We can't hide forever.
那个孩子呢  据说杀了父母的那个?
How about that kid?The one killed his parents?
-哦  他被抓了  -真的?
Oh, they got him. -They did?
他已经在看管之下
He's in custody.
我知道你的样子  你这狗杂种!
I know what you look like, you son of a bitch.
菲利·法尔曾
Philly Falzone.
你知道这里有人知道他的下落
Word is someone knows where Fibonacci is
无论如何也要想办法
and you're not doing anything about it.
帮帮我
Help me.
求你了
Please.
你要原谅这个孩子
You'll have to forgive my boy.
他老是做些不应该做的事
He has the propensity to be a bit gregarious when he shouldn't be.
在监狱的浴室总是感到很害怕
Fraternising in the prison shower. Come on.
也许你该让他歇一会
Maybe you oughta cut the kid a break.
你是不是对我的行为有意见啊  你没这么蠢吧
You wouldn't be meddling in my affairs,now, would you?You can't be that stupid.
现在我跟你算是同一条船上的人了
Not while I'm so fully invested in your affairs.
这是你们两个之间的事  与我无关
What's between you and him is between you and him.
我就这个意思
That's what I thought you said.
你一定要帮我
You've gotta help me.
You gotta help me.
你找错人了  这是警察的事
You talk to the wrong man.This is a matter for the police.
我说的可是我儿子
This is my son we're talking about.
看在上帝的份上  他失踪了  帮帮我!
For god say,He's missing. Do something!
你必须明白 我只是个监狱的狱长
You have got to understand,I am the warden of a prison.
牵涉到法律问题
When it comes to the law,
我完全无能为力
absolutely there is nothing I can do.
外面发生的事完全超出我的权力范围
Whatever happens is out of my jurisdiction
除非事情在里面
until it comes through those gates.
这就是里面的事!  放我出去!
It just did. Let me out.
-什么?  -让我去找他
-What?  -Let me find him.
我了解他的想法  我知道他会去哪
I know how he thinks.I know where he'd run.
布伦斯  现在跟你说清楚
I'd have thought
以目前的情况  你应该清楚自己是个死囚
by now you'd understand your position as a death row inmate.
这个忙我绝对帮不了
There is no way I can honour that request.
你说谎.你有这权力
That ain't true.You get the power.
如果犯人家属有紧急情况  你可以批准假释
In case of a family emergency,you can grant an inmate supervised leave.
你儿子现在是杀人案的首要嫌疑人!
Your son is a prime suspect in a double homicide.
你以为来干什么的  午休?
What do you think this is, a siesta?
看到没有?看到我的脸在上面没有?  知道这是什么意思吗?
You see that? You see my face up there?Any idea how it got there?
工作积极性
Work ethic.
这个词在你们国家有什么意义吗?
Those two words mean anything in your country?
你是狱工  在这里可不允许偷懒
You're on PI, so quit slow-walking me.
下次就不只是警告了
I'm not gonna warn you again.
看什么?!
What are you looking at?
狱警发现碎块  就会知道我们在挖洞
The bulls find this stuff,they'll know we're digging.
所以我们要把这些处理掉...
That's why we gotta get rid of it.
每次一小块
One piece at a time.
新人来了
Freshmen.
装得酷一点  伙计
Best put on ourjail face, BG.
那些家伙看到你愁眉苦脸  会把你烦到死的
These crabs see you puckering,they bitchify you in a heartbeat.
看来我现在得给你换个称呼了
I gotta find something else to call you now.
-为什么?  -因为你现在不是"嫩鸡"了
-Why's that?  -Cos you ain't a fish no more.
你现在不是监狱里最新的人...
You ain't the newest con in the tank.
我本来可以帮他的
I could've done something.
不  帝博格掌握那孩子的生死  你无能为力
No.T-Bag had his hooks in that kid.There was nothing you could have done.
我本可以告诉狱长
I could've told the Pope.
他就会被送到隔离区  这样就不会有事了
He could've transferred the kid to ADSEG.Then he will be in safe.
算了  迈克尔  你甚至都不认识他
Go easy, Michael. You didn't even know him.
这样就能心安理得?
And that makes it OK?
我因为怕惹麻烦而没去帮他
I turned my back on him because I didn't wanna make waves.
因为更容易...所以...无视这些事情
It was just... easier to look the other way,
-以保证计划的安全  -你做到了
-keep the plan safe. -And you did.
以什么样的代价?
But at what price?
妈妈可不是这样教我们的
That's not how she raised us.
别人有难 就要伸出援手
A man's down, you give him your hand.
如果她知道我成了这样的人  在坟墓里也会辗转反侧
She'd roll over in her grave if she knew.
不  不会的
She wouldn't.
你对我伸了援手  迈克尔
You've given me your hand, Michael.
我儿子在外面危在旦夕
My son's out there with a bull's eye on his back.
无论如何我们也要出去  求你
Do whatever you gotta do to get us out of here. Please.
你在干什么?
What are you doing?
只是想找点咖啡
I was just looking for some coffee.
对  没咖啡了
There isn't any.
那些是我父亲的  如果你想知道的话
They belonged to my father,if you were wondering.
在这放了多久了?
How long have they been in there?
不知道 五年吧
I don't know. Five years?
我跟你说  维罗妮卡  我们一起经历了那么多事
You know, Veronica, we've been through a lot
而且 跟你一样我现在也心烦意乱
and I'm freaking out here as much as you are,
但你看我的眼神有时候就像...
but you get this look in your eye sometimes like...
就像我是坏人
like I'm the bad guy.
我根本不了解你  尼克
I don't know who you are.
你只是像穿着闪亮铠甲的骑士一样  突然出现
You just magically show up like some knight in shining armour.
我今天才能没事
I'm really safe today.
我...我觉得你忽视了一些东西
You know, I think you seem to be forgetting something here.
我现在跟你一样处境危险
I'm in the cross hairs the same way you are,
都是为了你的前男友  这个人不是我父亲 只是个囚犯
all for your ex-boyfriend, I'm not my father who is a scumbag criminal
只是正好他被人陷害进了监狱
who just happens to be in prison for the one crime he didn't commit.
我告诉你  我受够了这些事情
You know something? I got enough of my own crap to deal with.
你要走就走
You wanna go, you go.
不介意我跟着你混吧  古沙?
Mind if I lamp with you, cuzzo?
滚蛋  小雪花(白人)
Roll, snowflake.
伙计  我只是...
Hey, man, I'm just...
我是新来的  明白?  我只是在找些伴儿
I'm just new, you know?I'm looking for some homies.
我说了  滚!
I said roll.
怎么了  我才刚到啊
Brother, I'm just launching.
是吗  那就到一边去  小白
Yeah? Well, launch somewhere else,white boy.
好的  伙计
All right, y'all.
我自己会走的
I'm fitting to bounce.
别激动
Peace.
那个小子没意识到自己的肤色啊
Boy's a bit confused about his pigmentation,
但他还是有勇气的  是吧
but he sure does have spunk, doesn't he?
阿布鲁奇?
Abruzzi!
-是?  -在干什么?
-Yeah?  -What are you doing?
你说"在干什么?" 是什么意思?
What do you mean, what am I doing?
月初就要到了  约翰
First of the month's coming up, John.
-怎么?  -这个月的我没拿到
-Yeah? So? -I haven't got my monthly.
-什么?  -我在网上查了我的帐户
-What? -I checked my balance.
看起来严重赤字啊
It's looking deficient.
肯定是有什么错误 比如结算问题
It's gotta be some kind of a mistake,like an accounting error.
对.
Yeah.
告诉法尔曾我不会接受  清算问题这种解释
Tell Falzone I don't stand for accounting errors.
今天结束前我会回办公室
I'm going back into my office at the end of the day.
再查我的收支情况
Gonna check my balance again.
如果没解决的话...
If it's not up to where it's supposed to be,
对你所有的照顾  比如负责P.I.
all these privileges you got,like running PI,
都会消失
they're gone.
搞定它  约翰
Get it done, John.
-法尔曾公司  -找菲利
-Falzone Enterprises. -Get Philly.
抱歉  法尔曾先生无法接电话
Mr Falzone's not available.
你告诉他约翰·阿布鲁奇打来的
You tell him it's John Abruzzi calling.
-对不起  我不知道是您...  -现在知道了?
-I'm sorry. I didn't realise. -Well, now you do.
抱歉  他过会儿打给你
I'm sorry. He's gonna have to call you back.
什么?  喂...
What?  Hey...
对不起  关于刚才的事
I'm sorry. About before.
大家都有压力  我知道
Pressure's getting to us, that's all.
好消息是没人找的到我们 我父亲帮我们做到这点
Good news is nobody can reach us out here.My old man made sure of that.
不要碰电话  还有井和发电机
Never even hooked up the telephone.Same with the well and the generator.
我曾想他是个阴谋论怪人
I used to think he was some kind of conspiracy theory wacko.
看来他是对的
Turns out maybe he was right.
我不能留下  尼克  我要回去
I can't stay, Nick.I'll get back.
他剩不到两个星期了
He's got less than two weeks.
他称这个是关键领带
The old man called this his serious tie.
只在他认为
He only wore it when he really,
重要时才戴
really meant business.
我们再露面会很危险
Be dangerous showing our faces again.
除非他们不再找我们  他们认为我们已经死了  是吧?
Not if they're not looking for us.They think we're dead.
我知道  但这样会持续很长吗?
Yeah, but how long is that gonna last?
要迅速  灵活应对
Gotta be quick, be smart about it.
依我看  我们只需要在一定范围调查
Wll,I see.We're just gonna be running in circles
在行刑前找到无罪的证据
if we think we can find exculpatory evidence before the execution.
证明他没做过
prove he didn't do it.
我差不多和库克郡的每个检察官都交过手
I've gone up against every prosecutor in Cook County.
一个男人被杀   他们第一个想联系的...
Man gets murdered, the first person they talk to
他真正的敌人的妻子
to see who his enemies were, the wife.
你要调查那个蜂王?
You wanna go after the queen bee herself?
莱斯利·斯特德曼
Leslie Steadman.
每个镇上的人都知道在勒星顿
Everyone in town knows the old bird lunches at the Lexington every day
还有社会集合
with the society set.
喂  慢点
Hey, hey. Hey, hey!Slow down!
慢点!
Slow down.
喂
Man,
你哥会让我们都暴露的
your brother's gonna give us away.
牛来了
Bull's coming.
-所以人都出去  -什么?
-Everybody out. -What?
我说了  所有人都出去!
I said everybody out.
就现在
Now.
快走
Move it!
-去哪啊  -向前  走到墙角
-Where are we going? -Around the corner.
在我去找你们前不要想动
And don't move a damn muscle till I come get you.
去吧
Go!
到底怎么了?
What the hell's going on?
-我们太坏了  是吧?  -你太坏了  走吧
-We're so bad, aren't we? -You're damn skippy. Let's go.
你下次应该多给点警报
You gotta give us more of a warning.
对不起
I'm sorry.
他突然出现
He just showed up.
我们会被抓的
Oh, we're gonna get caught
-被谁  -狱长
-by who? -by the warden.
宝贝  现在  在这儿
Baby, right now,in this room,
在这个时候
at this moment,
我就... 是狱长.
I am the warden.
-说啊  -我不会说的
-Then say it. -No.
说吧
Come on, baby, say it.
你就是狱长  路易斯!
You're the warden, Louis!
这对婊子养的
The sneaky son of a bitch.
你认为他发现那洞了
You think he found the hole?
再移一寸他就会发现了
Another inch and he'd have found it.
我们尽快得找点东西把洞口盖上
We need to find something to cover this hole ASAP.
破产  你说破产是指什么
Broke. What do you mean, broke?
公司
The C-Corp,
投资帐户
the investment accounts,
还有海边的百慕大鳄鱼产业
even the offshore stuff, Caymans, Bermuda...
菲利也会把帐算清
Philly Falzone liquidated everything.
我一开始就告诉过你   如果你惹我  下场会是如何
Hey, I told you from the beginning what would happen if you screwed me.
我注意了
and I heeded it.
这就是我一开始就警告过你  不要让菲利·鲍尔做你的律师
That's why I warned you from the get-go not to give Philly power of attorney.
我们谈过的  记得吗
We had that conversation, remember?
你实际剩下的钱就是  你妻子户头上的3万美元
Look, the only real funds you have left are the 30,000 in your wife's pocket account.
-我现在可以...  -不要动那些钱  不要碰
-Now, I can...  -Don't. Don't touch that.
除了我妻子以外谁也不能碰那笔钱
Nobody touches that but her.
我要告诉她什么
What do I tell her?
-你知道所有的事情吗  -什么也别告诉她
-You know, about all this? -Don't tell her anything,
好吗
OK?
破产声明马上就要到了
The statements are going to come.
她会知道的   嘿  我告诉过你
She's going to know. Hey, I told you.
别告诉她
Don't tell her.
好吗
All right?
有问题吗
You got a problem with that?
没问题 约翰
OK, John.
如果还有其他需要帮助的  你就联系我
You know where to contact me if you need anything else.
有事的话你也可以找我
The same goes for you.
嘿
Hey.
嘿!
Hey!
菲利
Philly.
最近好吗
Aren't you?
见到你真好  对于你答案永远是是的 菲利
So good to see you.For you, the answer's always yes, Philly.
请坐
Sit down.
坐
Sit.
过来  约翰
Come on, John.
代理的卫生组织或是首选供应商  列表上好像没有福克斯河药业的记录
There's no record of a Fox River medical practice on our list of participating HMOs or PPOs.
是的  那是因为我们是州立监狱
That's because we're a state penitentiary
而且我们这里情况特殊
and we're in kind of a unique situation here.
斯科菲尔德先生的上一个老板  给他的保险还没有失效
Mr Scofield's insurance policy from his previous employer hasn't lapsed.
所以州里命令你支付他的经费  而不是用纳税人的钱
The state's demanding that you pay for his treatment and not the taxpayers.
好的
OK. Well,
另外 听说他已经补上了免税的部分
it says here he already met his deductible.
好的
OK.
哦   不   等等  这是精神病类保险  不是常规类...
Oh, no, wait. That's his psych deductible,not his medical.
对不起 精神是指精神病类?
Sorry. Psych as in psychiatric?
我允许你给菲利打电话了?
I give you permission to call Philly?
伙计  我问你问题呢
Hey, I asked you a question, man.
听着
Listen. There, uh...
这儿的规矩得变变
there's been a restructuring.
这是菲利自己说的
This comes from Philly himself.
你用不着递话  菲波纳奇
You couldn't deliver Fibonacci,
我现在是这儿的老大
so I'm the man in here now.
听着  吉利
Listen.
去商品给我买一袋薯条
Run to the commissary and get me a packet of chips.
我就当什么事都没发生过
We'll pretend this never happened.
好的  我告诉你  约翰
No, I'm telling you, John.
你越早面对这些事实 我们相处地就会越好
The sooner you face these facts, the better off we will all be.
我可以让你死于心脏病
I can kill you in a heartbeat.
我对此表示怀疑
Somehow, I doubt that.
你越早面对这些事实  我们相处地就会越好
The sooner you face facts,the better off we will all be.
你已经过气了  约翰
You're yesterday's news, John.
这是在干吗?  对付黑人?
What's the word? Y'all cooking brownies?
-规矩点  -什么意思?
-Act your race, milk chicken. -What's the deal, yo?
人多势众怎么着?
You got tough buckets or something?
你在给白人丢脸  知道吗
You're a disgrace to your skin,you know that?
那小子只是滑倒了
The boy just slipped.
只是滑倒了
是不是?
Ain't that right?
起来
Come on. Stand up.
好了  都回到牢房里
Cons, let's get back to your cells.
你叫什么名字
What's your name, boy?
-是谁  -斯特内
-Who's that? -Stolte.
斯特内  你知道我儿子的事了吧  是不是
Stolte. You've heard about my kid, right?
把盘子拿去  林肯
Take the tray, Linc.
我
I, uh...
我只要求给他打个电话
I just need to call him.
接着盘子  林肯
Just take the tray,
再不接 我就把它推进去  那你就要在地上吃了
or I'm gonna shove it in there and you can eat it off the ground.
你也有一个儿子
You have a son.
叫乔伊
Josh.
林肯 别做蠢事
Don't do anything stupid, Linc.
不会的  我...
I'm not.
我问一个问题就让你走
I just wanna ask you a question,then I'm gonna let go.
要是是你儿子你怎么办?
What if it were Josh?
如果碰到是你儿子呢？
What if it were your son?
求你了
Please.
爸?
Dad?
LJ  谢天谢地.  你没事吧？
LJ. Thank God. Are you all right?
不好
No.
我现在不知道身在何处
Nowhere near it.
什么意思?   你现在哪儿?
What do you mean? Where are you?
他们讲的关于我的事情  都是假的
What they're saying about me, it's not true.
-我知道  -是他们杀了妈妈
-I know it's not true. -They killed her.
他们杀了她  他们...
They killed her.
就在我眼前  我目睹了一切  天哪
Right in front of me.Right in front of my eyes.
你要...你要...
You gotta...
-他们为什么这样做?  -听着  孩子  你要学会坚强
-Why are they doing this?  -You gotta step up.
要像个大人一样  懂我的意思吗?
You gotta be the man now.You understand me?
-明白吗  LJ?  -嗯
-You understand me, LJ?  -OK.
好  现在我要你打电话给维罗妮卡
Ok,I want you to call Veronica.
她的电话打不通  我之前打过了
Her number is disconnected. I already tried.
打给尼克·萨维恩  "终极司法"的那个
Nick Savrinn. You call Nick Savrinn.Works for Project Justice.
我们说完之后你打给他.
You call him once we're done.
-记住了吗?   -尼克·萨维恩
-You got it? -Nick Savrinn. OK.
-恩  好的  我会打的 会打的  -坚持住 伙计
-OK, I'll call. I'll call. -All right, man.
好
OK.
他们在这
They're here.
谁在那儿?
Who's here?
LJ?  LJ?!
你听到了吗?
You hear that?
Did you hear it?
你知道那意味着什么吗?
You know what that means?
为什么不去问问你妈那意味着什么?
Why don't you ask your mom what it means?
哦  对不起  从她那里得到回答应该有点困难
Oh, I'm sorry. You might have trouble getting an answer out of her right about now, huh?
LJ?
-我看到信息了 -才刚联系到  别担心
-I saw that. -Just getting connected, that's all.
就是她
There she is.
斯蒂德曼 夫人?
Mrs Steadman?
我是迪克·斯勒 这是我的助理  法兰西·凯丽
I'm Dick Sisler.This is my assistant Francette Kelly
我们都是国家受害者联合会的
We're the National Victims' Rights Association.
我们为暴力犯罪的受害者提供帮助
We provide assist victims of violent crimes,
为涉嫌犯罪的政治领导候选人给予帮助
gather support for tough-on-crime politicians.
真伟大
grandeur
如果你们组织在寻求资金支持
Look,If your organisation's looking for a hand-out,
年轻人 请和我的商业部经理去交涉
Young man you can go through my business manager.
夫人  我们不是为此事而来  事实上  可以坐下说吗?
Ma'am, that is not why we're here, actually.May we sit down?
我们希望您能就众多案件的  一件提供些帮助
We hoped you could help us with one of our more public cases.
是林肯·布伦斯一案
The Lincoln Burrows case.
如您所知  他因那些伪造的证据被起诉  事实上他是无辜的
As you know,He's making claims that he's innocent,
是其他人蓄意谋杀了您丈夫
that others had motive to murder your husband.
我实在没有时间听你们长篇大论
I don't have time for a long conversation.
斯蒂德曼夫人  不会耽误您太久的
It doesn't have to be long conversation.
如果要谈谁有谋杀特伦斯的动机
If we talked about who had motive to kill Terrence,
我们可以在这里呆上整天
we'd be here all day.
-什么意思?  -看看周围
-I'm sorry? -Look around.
这里有一半人是他公司的股东
Half the people here were shareholders in his company.
每个人都在装着悼念他
Every one of them sat at my husband's memorial
但每个人都有同样一个想法
and every one of them was thinking the same thing:
"谢天谢地他终于死了"
"Thank God he's gone."
-为什么会这样想?  -钱
-Why would they think that?  -Money.
指控的流言一传开
As soon as rumours of the indictment started,
他们就开始作鸟兽散
they ran for the exits.
我没听过指控的事
I wasn't aware of any indictment.
从没被证实过  还没开始他就死了
It never came down. He died before it could.
-跟公司有关系吗?  -你可以算一下
-Anything to do with Ecofield? -Do the math.
公司总裁被指控诈骗  投资者就会损失钱
CEO gets indicted for fraud.Investors start losing money.
大笔的钱
Lots of money.
要不是我还不确定  是不是布伦斯开的枪
If I didn't know Burrows pulled that trigger,
我可能会怀疑这个餐厅里的任何一个人
I'd say it was any one of these people in the restaurant.
这可是5亿美元啊  斯勒先生
We're talking half a billion dollars.
这笔钱要让人去杀人绰绰有余了
People have killed for a lot less.
左右不是人  是吧?
Not a good position you find yourself in, is it?
白人不要你  黑人也不要你
Whites don't want you. Blacks don't want you.
你刚好卡在中间了  不是吗?
You're just caught in the middle, aren't you?
标准的"左右不靠"
A regular 'tweener.
我跟你不是同一路人
We're different, you and me, lot of ways.
但有趣的是  我们还有很多相似之处
But, you know,the funny thing is we're also a lot alike.
一对没人爱的可怜小狗
Couple of dogs with runny noses that nobody loves.
膝盖怎么样了  问一下?
How's that knee, by the way?
-你搞什么?  -不 不 不
-What the hell are you doing?  -No no no
别误解我  我只是跟你做朋友
Don't get me wrong. I'm just a friend.
对  "亲密"朋友  我可不要这个
A fruity friend. I don't need none of that.
-别激动  -不  不  不
-Easy. -No. No.
你嘴里说得好听 却心怀鬼胎  你这死同性恋
You think you're getting up in this,you got another thing coming, you homo.
你嘴巴很不检点  你知道吗?
You got a foul mouth, you know that?
没错  你敢再靠近我  我会杀了你
Yeah. I do.And you come near me again,I'm gonna kill you.
哦  那你尽管来吧  小朋友
Well, then,you're just gonna have to, little man.
你最好睁着眼睡觉  娘娘腔
You sleep with one eye open,girly.
-放马过来  贱货  -我会的  我会的
-Bring it on.bitch  -Oh, I'm gonna
-我会来的  -你最好别缠着那孩子
-I'll gonna bring it on in spades..  -You oughta leave that kid alone.
你最好别多管闲事  嗯?
Maybe you are in no position to be telling me my business. Hm?
就这么简单
That's what I thought.
你肯定理解  我不能谈论以前的病人
I'm sure you can understand my reluctance to discuss past patients.
当然
absolutely
呃  不过我也知道根据HIPAA法案 (健康保险便携与核算法案)
My understanding is that under HIPAA
只要病人被转移治疗  我们可以共享资料
we're allowed to share information as long as it furthers the care of the patient.
我不太习惯这样质问别人 但是  我...
I'm not accustomed to making enquiries like this, but I...
我感觉我可以治好他
I feel like I can get through to him.
我可以帮他
I can help him.
可以想像  他在那确实需要帮助
I imagine he needs it in there.
你给他治疗什么病?
What did you treat him for?
迈克尔有好几种病
Michael suffered from a couple of things.
其中一种叫做"潜在抑制症"
One was a condition called low latent inhibition.
不好意思  我不太懂术语
Sorry. I'm not familiar with the term.
这种病人看到的东西跟我们不一样
People who suffer from low latent inhibition see everyday things like you or I do
比如灯  做个例子
like this lamp.
但我们眼中只能看到灯的形象
But where we just process the image of a lamp,
他们能看到一切
they process everything.
支架  灯泡  螺钉 甚至里面的垫圈
The stem, the bulb, the bolts,even the washers inside.
他们的脑子对周围事物的信息更开放
Their brains are more open to incoming stimuli in the surrounding environment.
其他人的脑子
Other people's brains
像你和我 则把这些信息关在外面
yours and mine -shut out the same information.
我们这么做是为了保持心智健全
We have to do it in order to keep our sanity.
如果智商低的人患了"潜在抑制症"
If someone with a low IQ has low latent inhibition,
结果通常是精神分裂
it almost always results in mental illness.
但如果患者有足够高的智商
But if someone has a high IQ,
结果通常是极具创造性的天才
it almost always results in creative genius.
你认为迈克尔是天才吗?
Do you think Michael's a genius?
这个词已经被当今媒体毁了
Well, I think that word's been derogated in the media these days.
不过以这个词的本意来讲  没错  是的
But in the classic sense of the word, yes, I do.
你说他还有其它疾病
You... you said there was something else you treated him for?
他刚来的时候非常没有自信心
He came to me with absolutely no sense of self-worth.
失去双亲的孩子通常都会这样
The loss of both parents very often does that to a child.
但由于"潜在抑制症"
But with the low latent inhibition,
迈克尔身上发生了一些有趣的事
something interesting happened to Michael.
他变得对周围的苦难有强烈的共鸣
He became very attuned to all the suffering around him.
他无法坐视不管
He couldn't shut it out.
他成了帮助者
He became a rescuer,
这种人关心其他人的幸福  远多过关心自己
one of those people who are more concerned with other people's welfare than their own.
这些我一点都不了解
I didn't know all this about him.
那说明你不了解迈克尔·斯科菲尔德
Then maybe you don't know Michael Scofield.
没错
Yeah.
我的语音信箱有新消息
I checked my voicemail at work.
林肯的儿子Lj刚给我留了言
Lincoln's son LJ just left me a message.
他有麻烦了
He's in trouble.
-谁?  -LJ  我是维罗妮卡  你在哪?
-Hello? -LJ, it's Veronica. Where are you?
噢  维罗妮卡  我不知道
Oh, Veronica, I don't know.
你必须来接我
You gotta come get me.
我么不行知道吗? 我们不在芝加哥  你要过来找我们
We can't, OK? We're not in Chicago.You have to come to us.
好吧  你们在哪?
Oh. All right. Where's that?
-他们到底怎么知道我在哪的?  -怎么了?
-Oh. How the hell do they know where I am?  -What's going on?
他们为什么总是知道我在哪的?
How do they know where I am?
LJ...
-LJ 你听我说  -你不知道
-LJ, I want you to listen to me.  -No,you haven't get the mean...
-我去任何地方  他们都能找到  -我要你听我说  好吗?
-Everywhere I go, they're there. -I want you to listen to me, OK?
我需要你来找我们  我们在莫萨湖
I need you to come to us. We're in Lake Mercer.
-那是什么地方?  -是一个小镇
-Where's that?  -On the lowa border.
在爱荷华州边境  那有个车站
On the lowa border.There's a bus station.
去买张车票  我们会在那儿接你
We'll meet you there.
还好  他们还活着
They're still alive.
看来可以一箭三雕了
The bird in the hand just became three.
我们走
Let's go.
-但是这孩子就在...  -我们走
-But the kid's right...  -Let's go.
他们走了  他们走了
They're leaving. They're leaving.
LJ我要你仔细听我说  好吗?
LJ, I need to know that you hear me, OK?
莫萨湖
Lake Mercer.
莫萨湖  知道了
Lake Mercer. OK.
好的  到时候见
All right, bye.
车子几分钟后就将从6号站发车
Your bus leaves from depot six in just a few minutes.
谢谢
Thanks.
我  呃...
I...
只是想让你知道如果你想在这找人谈谈  我原意
just wanted you to know that if you're looking for someone to talk to, you're not alone.
帮助犯人解决困难也是我工作的一部分
It's part of my job to counsel inmates and help them with their problems.
我想我自己能把事情处理好的
I got things pretty well figured out.
我了解了一些你的背景
I sort of backed into some information about you.
我希望你不介意
I hope you don't mind,
你要明白我成为医生的初衷  就是想帮助别人
but there's a reason I became a doctor.
这是我的本能
It's in my nature to want to help.
从我理解的角度 这也是你的天性
From what I understand,it's in your nature too.
你来这之前作了很多的工作
You did a lot of good things before you were in here.
很多社会工作 很多慈善事业
Lot community work, lot charity work.
发生了什么?
What happened?
你谈论的那个男人  进这地方那一刻就已经死了
The man you're talking about died the moment I stepped inside these walls.
好吧
All right.
先生女士们  美国特工
Ladies and gentlemen,United States Secret Service.
请保持镇静
Please remain calm.
呆在你的位置不要动
Remain where you are.
来
Come here.
没事了
It's OK.
他们走了
They're leaving.
扔掉你的手机  他们在跟踪你  我们在格拉鲁斯
Dump the phone.they're tracking you.We're in New Glarus.
你现在安全了
You're safe now, all right?
收到一份你代理律师发来的文件
You received communication from your attorney.
在这签名
Please sign this document
保证你这份文件里面不含非法以及
certifying that I inspected it for contraband
违背律师的权利的内容
without at any time breaching attorney-client privilege
惠特曼先生六年级的生物课笔记
Notes from Mrs.Weatman's 6th Grade Biology Class
LJ  我和维罗妮卡在一起  我很好  我爱你
Lj,I'm with Mrs.Veronica.I'm okay.I love you.
你在笑什么?
What are you grinning about?
噢  只是在想我很快就会从这鬼地方出去了
I'm gonna be out in the real world in a bit.
其实是我要搞到最后一个小跟班了哈
The fact that I'm gonna get me one fine piece of tail certainly don't hurt either.
没什么比这更让人兴奋了 是不  斯科菲尔德
Nothing like tail, eh, Scofield?
婊子养的!
Son of a bitch!
你给我听好
This ends right now.
噢  你刚惹了一个职业大嗓门   小伙子
Oh, you just screwed some major league pooch, pretty.
我将会象1000支鸭子那样唱歌
I'm gonna sing like a whole tree full of birds now.
-警卫!  -你想唱?  那唱好了
-Badge! -You wanna sing, then sing.
但是你知道我怎么想吗?
But you know what I think?
你手上没有什么砝码
You don't have the guts.
你和我们一样想尽快离开这鬼地方
You want out of here just as much as the rest of us.
这里有人想找麻烦吗
We got a problem here?
没
No.
我  呃...
I, uh...
我...我刚发现其实工具没有少  我的错
I thought we was missing some tools here.My bad.
回去工作
Get back to work.
现在...
Now.
你和我是拴在一根绳上的蚂蚱
You and I may be stuck together in this little dance,
但是这里我说了算
but I call the shots.
外面的那个孩子
First shot, that kid out there,
再也不要去动他
you don't touch him ever.
明白了?
Do we understand each other?
明白
We do.
闪开  朱利欧
Out of the way, Julio.
阿布鲁奇
Abruzzi.
你和我  咱们出去聊聊
You and me,we're gonna have a conversation.
他怎么没陷下去?
How come he didn't fall through?
什么?
What?
我提醒过你
I warned you.
我会搞定的
I'll get it together.
再给我点时间
You gotta give me more time.
你已经用完你的时间了  约翰
You've had your time, John.
你跌跟头了  爱丽丝?
You tripping on something, Alice?
哈  正如我所料
Yeah. That's what I thought.
你再敢在这出现 我让你吃不了兜着走
Lamp it up in here again,I'll be fixing to break some shop.
我们有麻烦了
Uh-oh. We got a problem.
贝利克
Bellick.
老大?
Boss.
老大
发生什么了? 他们在这做什么?
What's happening?What are they doing?
-整修那间烧毁的房子  -你在说什么?
-Fixing the break room.  -What are you talking about?
那是P.I.做的事  不是我来安排的吗?
That's PI.I run it.
不再是了
Not any more, you don't.